A Guide to the Papers of Charles King 1888-1929
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Charles King, 1888-1929
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
7491-a
This collection consists of 25 items.
Charles King
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was given to the Library on [December 17, 1963] January 27, 1965.
Scope and Content Information
This collections consists of 23 letters from Charles King to various recepients, including J. M. Stoddart, S. S. McClure, J. S. Phillips, E. S. Goodhue, J. Herbert Low, C. Graham Bacon, Charles T. Howard, and Vincent Starrett. There is also a notation of "Owen Meredith's " Lucile", and a photograph of "Captain Charles King."
Arrangement
This collection is arranged chronologically.
Contents List
- Letters
  - Charles King to [J. M.] Stoddart 1888 November 20, ALS, 2 p.
    Thanks Stoddart for magazines sent and discusses his work.
  - C. K. to S. S. McClure or [John Sanborn] Phillips 1889 January 21, ALS, 2 p.
    Writes that he has been sick but will send chapter of story tonight and others will follow quickly.
  - C. K. to S. S. McClure 1889 January 26, ALS, 2 p.
    Has sent copy and more will follow. Will have to submit to operation follwed by rest. Hopes to be well enough to travel to Philadelphia and New York by March.
  - C. K. to [J. S.] Phillips 1889 February 14, ALS, 3 p.
    Discusses his proposed writings and prices. Plans to be in New York in March or April.
  - C. K. to J. S. Phillips 1889 February 24, ALS, 1 p.
    Will come to New York about March 8 and requests magazine copies with "Queen of Bedlam."
  - C. K. to J. S. Phillips 1889 April 15, ALS, 1 p.
    Questions action to be taken regarding a column published in the Chicago Times copying an article written for Phillips.
  - C. K. to J. S. Phillips 1889 May 12, ALS, 1 p.
    Has not had time to write the story. Has a proposal for Mr. McClure when he returns. A copy of photograph of Capt. Charles King is attached to the letter.
  - Press Supply Association to C. K., and his reply 1980 April 19, ALS, 1 p.
    Association requestion C. K.'s opinion concerning the necessity of a college education for a man pursuing a business career. C. K. answers that the methodical habits needed for business success are not gained in college; however, a college education will make his old age and wealth far the sweeter.
  - C. K. to [J. M.] Stoddart 1891 November 8, ALS, 3 p.
    Requests copies of "Portica." Another story is near completion; discusses possible titles.
  - C. K. to [J. M.] Stoddart 1892 December 23, ALS 1 p.
    Has received check, and has sent final chapter of story.
  - C. K. to J. M. Stoddart [1894] April 8, ALS, 3 p.
    Requests confidential reply from Stoddart concerning the terms of payment for the current story. Would like a lump sum payment rather than the usual pecentage.
  - C. K. to E. S. Goodhue 1896 July 19, ALS, 2 p.
    Thanks Goodhue for the honorary membership in the Koloa Kodak Klub and comments on his use of his Kodak camera.
  - C. K. to J. Herbert Low 1897 September 22, APCS, 1 p.
    Writes that his character Billy Ray was drawn from life.
  - C. K. to C. Graham Bacon 190[2] January 19, ALS, 2 p.
    Sends autograph for Mrs. Bacon and thanks Bacon for invitation to call next time he is in New York. Bacon was former adjutant of the Seventh (cavalry) under C. K.
  - C. K. to Charles T. Howard 1910 February 24, ALS, 2 p.
    Advises Howard he will sign and return book if sent.
  - C. K. to Charles T. Howard 1910 March 5, APCS, 1 p.
    Advises Howard he has received his letter of February 28 but has not received book.
  - C. K. to Charles T. Howard 1910 March 20, APCS, 1 p.
    Acknowledges letter of March 14 but no book. Suggests the Post Office investigate.
  - C. K. to [Charles T.] Howard 1910 April 4, ALS, 1 p.
    Advises he will have second book held in Milwaukee until he returns.
  - C. K. to Charles T. Howard 1911 May 23, APCS, 1 p.
    Has found lost book, Lanier, in cleaning. Suggests he could send another book instead.
  - C. K. to Charles T. Howard 1911 May 31, ALS w/env., 1 p.
    Is sending the book Lanier today
  - C. K. to Charles T. Howard 1911 July 5, APCS, 1 p.
    Thanks Howard for The Clammer and advises he will take it to camp tomorrow.
  - C. K. to Vincent Starrett 1929 February 8, ALS w/ env., 2 p.
    Gives his version of his troop's encounter with the Cheyenne years before, and the part Cody played. Also mentions other writings concerning this action, including Campaigning with Crook.
  - C. K. to [J. S.] Phillips n.y. March 16, ALS, 1 p.
    With page from book containing 4 photographs of King. C. K. requests that balance of money of "Queen of Bedlam" be sent to him in Milwaukee.
- Miscellaneous
  - Notation: "Owen Meredith's "Lucile" n.d., ANS
    Signed by C. K. mounted on note paper
- Photo
  - "Captain Charles King," head and shoulders ante 1892, Magazine photo